<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
	<id>com.jetbrains.PyCharm-Professional</id>
	<metadata_license>CC-BY-SA</metadata_license>
	<name>PyCharm-Professional</name>
	<summary>The most intelligent Python IDE</summary>
	<description>
		<p>PyCharm is designed by programmers, for programmers, to provide all the tools you need for productive Python development.</p>
		<p>PyCharm provides smart code completion, code inspections, on-the-fly error highlighting and quick-fixes, along with automated code refactorings and rich navigation capabilities.</p>
		<p>PyCharm offers great framework-specific support for modern web development frameworks such as Django, Flask, Google App Engine, Pyramid, and web2py.</p>
		<p>PyCharm integrates with IPython Notebook, has an interactive Python console, and supports Anaconda as well as multiple scientific packages including matplotlib and NumPy.</p>
		<p>In addition to Python, PyCharm supports JavaScript, CoffeeScript, TypeScript, Cython, SQL, HTML/CSS, template languages, AngularJS, Node.js, and more.</p>
		<p>A huge collection of tools out of the box: an integrated debugger and test runner; Python profiler; a built-in terminal; and integration with major VCS and built-in Database Tools.</p>
		<p>NOTE: This package is not verified by, affiliated with, or supported by JetBrains s.r.o. </p>
	</description>
	<url type="homepage">http://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/</url>
	<url type="bugtracker">https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/</url>
	<url type="help">https://www.jetbrains.com/help/pycharm/</url>
	<launchable type="desktop-id">com.jetbrains.PyCharm-Professional.desktop</launchable>
	<releases>
		<release version="2025.3" date="2025-12-08">
			<description></description>
		</release>
		<release version="2025.2.5" date="2025-11-28">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2025.2.4" date="2025-10-23">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2025.2.3" date="2025-10-03">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2025.2.2" date="2025-09-22">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2025.2.1.1" date="2025-09-03">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2025.2.0.1" date="2025-08-12">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2025.2" date="2025-08-04">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2025.1.3.1" date="2025-07-11">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2025.1.3" date="2025-07-03">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2025.1.2" date="2025-06-11">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2025.1.1.1" date="2025-05-15">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2025.1" date="2025-04-16">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.3.5" date="2025-03-19">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.3.4" date="2025-02-27">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.3.3" date="2025-02-13">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.3.2" date="2025-01-28">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.3.1.1" date="2024-12-19">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.3.1" date="2024-12-12">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.3" date="2024-11-13">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.2.4" date="2024-10-23">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.2.3" date="2024-09-26">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.2.2" date="2024-09-19">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.2.1" date="2024-08-29">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.2.0.1" date="2024-08-20">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.2" date="2024-08-12">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.1.5" date="2024-08-06">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.1.4" date="2024-06-25">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.1.3" date="2024-06-10">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.1.2" date="2024-05-29">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.1.1" date="2024-04-30"/>
		<release version="2024.1" date="2024-04-04"/>
		<release version="2023.3.5" date="2024-03-21"/>
		<release version="2023.3.4" date="2024-02-26"/>
		<release version="2023.3.3" date="2024-01-26"/>
		<release version="2023.3.2" date="2023-12-20"/>
		<release version="2023.3.1" date="2023-12-12"/>
		<release version="2023.3" date="2023-12-06"/>
		<release version="2023.2.5" date="2023-11-14"/>
		<release version="2023.2.4" date="2023-11-01"/>
		<release version="2023.2.3" date="2023-10-12"/>
		<release version="2023.2.2" date="2023-10-02"/>
		<release version="2023.2.1" date="2023-08-24"/>
		<release version="2023.2" date="2023-07-26"/>
		<release version="2023.1.4" date="2023-07-13"/>
		<release version="2023.1.3" date="2023-06-21"/>
		<release version="2023.1.2" date="2023-05-17"/>
		<release version="2023.1.1" date="2023-04-28"/>
		<release version="2023.1" date="2023-03-30"/>
		<release version="2022.3.3" date="2023-03-10"/>
		<release version="2022.3.2" date="2023-01-26"/>
		<release version="2022.3.1" date="2022-12-28"/>
		<release version="2022.3" date="2022-12-01"/>
		<release version="2022.2.4" date="2022-11-17"/>
		<release version="2022.2.3" date="2022-10-11"/>
		<release version="2022.2.2" date="2022-09-15"/>
		<release version="2022.2.1" date="2022-08-17"/>
		<release version="2022.2" date="2022-07-28">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Python 3.11: Code insight for exception groups and <code>except*</code> operator.</li>
					<li>Python 3.11: Code insight for the new <code>Required[ ]</code> and <code>NotRequired[ ]</code> notations for individual TypedDict keys.</li>
					<li>HTTP-client: Support for WebSocket connections.</li>
					<li>New UI for setting up remote interpreters.</li>
					<li>Initial support for PyScript.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2022.1.4" date="2022-07-21"/>
		<release version="2022.1.3" date="2022-06-22"/>
		<release version="2022.1.2" date="2022-06-01"/>
		<release version="2022.1.1" date="2022-05-12"/>
		<release version="2022.1" date="2022-04-13">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Authentication Support for Custom Package Repositories: Configure basic HTTP authentication to access custom package repositories and easily manage dependencies via PyCharm without switching to the terminal for manual installation.</li>
					<li>Improved TypedDict Support: PyCharm makes it easy to use <em>dict</em> literals as arguments for functions or to instantiate objects from classes where <em>TypedDict</em> is expected by providing code completion for the available keys.</li>
					<li>New Services UI for Docker: We’ve significantly reworked Docker’s UI in the <em>Services</em> tool window to give you much clearer control of your containers, images, networks, and volumes.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2021.3.3" date="2022-03-17"/>
		<release version="2021.3.2" date="2022-01-31"/>
		<release version="2021.3.1" date="2021-12-29"/>
		<release version="2021.3" date="2021-12-01">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Poetry support: In response to a very popular request in our issue tracker, we’ve added Poetry support to PyCharm, including code completion for your pyproject.toml file out of the box!</li>
					<li>New FastAPI project type: When creating a new project, select the FastAPI project type to have PyCharm Pro import dependencies and create run/debug configurations for you.</li>
					<li>New Jupyter notebook experience: We have been working hard to improve the PyCharm experience for software engineers working within the data science space. PyCharm Pro brings a new UI for notebooks, support for popular shortcuts and interactive outputs, and more.</li>
					<li>Remote development support (beta): PyCharm Pro now supports a Beta version of the remote development workflow. You can now connect to remote machines from anywhere in the world, run PyCharm’s backend, and take advantage of remote computing power while feeling as though everything is running locally.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2021.2.3" date="2021-10-20"/>
		<release version="2021.2.2" date="2021-09-15"/>
		<release version="2021.2.1" date="2021-08-27"/>
		<release version="2021.2" date="2021-07-28">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Python 3.10 support: for pattern matching and the new syntax for union types, you can now format, inspect, and use code completion for these language structures.</li>
					<li>HTML preview: reload pages in the browser on save.</li>
					<li>Collaborative development: Python Console in Code With Me for both guests and hosts.</li>
					<li>Tool window for Python packages: install packages from custom locations.</li>
					<li>Code completion of fields and operators in the MongoDB console.</li>
					<li>Pre-commit checks: ability to run tests.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2021.1.3" date="2021-06-30"/>
		<release version="2021.1.2" date="2021-06-02"/>
		<release version="2021.1.1" date="2021-04-22"/>
		<release version="2021.1" date="2021-04-07">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Faster indexing.</li>
					<li>Enhanced WSL 2 support.</li>
					<li>Code insight: Auto import on module member completion.</li>
					<li>Tool window for Python packages.</li>
					<li>Collaborative development tool: Code With Me.</li>
					<li>Built-in HTML preview.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2020.3.5" date="2021-03-26"/>
		<release version="2020.3.4" date="2021-03-17"/>
		<release version="2020.3.3" date="2021-01-27"/>
		<release version="2020.3.2" date="2020-12-30"/>
		<release version="2020.3.1" date="2020-12-21"/>
		<release version="2020.3" date="2020-12-02">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Environment autoconfiguration for imported or cloned projects: If you are cloning or importing a project from the repo with a requirements.txt, setup.py, environment.yml, or pipfile inside it, PyCharm will set up a Python environment for you.</li>
					<li>Search Everywhere to find Git commits: Search Everywhere now also looks for your Git commits. Press Shift twice to open Search Everywhere and start searching. The search dialog can also now be used for performing basic math calculations.</li>
					<li>Create a React component from usage: Have an unresolved React component in your code? Place the caret at its location, press Alt+Enter,and select Create class / function component from the list. The IDE will create the relevant code construct for you.</li>
					<li>New Welcome screen for faster initial setup: The initial setup wizard has been redesigned to give you quick access to your projects and to allow you to quickly customize your IDE. Cultivate your knowledge of the IDE with a new Learn PyCharm section.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2020.2.5" date="2020-12-02"/>
		<release version="2020.2.4" date="2020-11-27"/>
		<release version="2020.2.3" date="2020-10-07"/>
		<release version="2020.2.2" date="2020-09-17"/>
		<release version="2020.2.1" date="2020-08-26"/>
		<release version="2020.2" date="2020-07-29">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Full GitHub pull request support: You no longer need to switch between the browser and your IDE to manage anything in your GitHub Pull Request workflow.</li>
					<li>Smart in-editor exceptions preview: Don't spend time browsing your code after exceptions. PyCharm now automatically finds and displays it directly in your editor.</li>
					<li>In-place signature-change refactoring: Simply add, remove, or edit your method signature in-place and apply project-wide refactorings without going through pop-up dialogs.</li>
					<li>Support for Django configuration constants completion in settings.py: Stop typing the same Django configuration variables over and over again. Speed up your flow and let PyCharm autocomplete documented Django settings for you.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2020.1.4" date="2020-07-22"/>
		<release version="2020.1.3" date="2020-07-08"/>
		<release version="2020.1.2" date="2020-06-03"/>
		<release version="2020.1.1" date="2020-05-07"/>
		<release version="2020.1" date="2020-04-08">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Interactive Rebasing: Commits can get messy, which is why you need to be able to rebase your branch. Now, PyCharm allows you to do so visually and with unprecedented ease.</li>
					<li>Smarter Debugging: PyCharm’s debugger now makes it easy to see what’s happening in the middle of a complex statement. When stepping in, the debugger will ask you exactly what part of the statement you want to investigate further.</li>
					<li>JetBrains Mono: PyCharm helps you read your code by navigating your project effectively, and now also by presenting your code in a font designed specifically for it.</li>
					<li>Django Template Imports: PyCharm Professional Edition makes life easy for web developers by offering code completion (and debugging) in Django templates. We’ve made a couple improvements on this front: auto import for custom tags and better completion.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2019.3.4" date="2020-03-18"/>
		<release version="2019.3.3" date="2020-02-07"/>
		<release version="2019.3.2" date="2020-01-22"/>
		<release version="2019.3.1" date="2019-12-19"/>
		<release version="2019.3" date="2019-12-01">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Interactive Widgets for Jupyter Notebooks. A picture is worth a thousand words, but making it interactive really makes your data come to life. Interactive widgets are now supported in PyCharm.</li>
					<li>MongoDB Support. One of the most commonly used NoSQL databases is now supported by the database tools included in PyCharm Professional Edition.</li>
					<li>We’ve completed support for all Python 3.8 features: you can now expect PyCharm-grade code completion when you use TypedDicts. We’ve also added support for Literal type annotations, and more.</li>
					<li>Why is it that when you get a CSV file, it always has a very long name which is very prone to typos? We’ve now added a small convenience feature that’ll save you: completion for filenames in methods like open and Panda’s read_csv.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2019.2.3" date="2019-09-25"/>
		<release version="2019.2" date="2019-07-24">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Jupyter Notebook Integration has been improved. Some of the most highly requested Jupyter Notebook features have been implemented in this version. Now you will be able run all cells with a single button click, select and configure your Jupyter server using a specific project and port to listen to, keep track of variables while debugging them by getting their current state, restart the kernel and publish notebooks from PyCharm to JetBrains Datalore</li>
					<li>Syntax highlight support for many other languages has been added. Do you work on projects where code in a different language sneaks into your project? PyCharm will now highlight the syntax of Windows .bat files, C#, C++, Groovy, Lua, Makefiles, and more</li>
					<li>We are adding support for some major Python 3.8 features. Try out positional-only parameters, variable assignment within expressions, ‘Final’ qualifier to restrict usage of methods, classes and variables, and new ways to use f-strings to present values and variables</li>
					<li>cURL format is now supported for HTTP requests. Just copy your cURL formatted request and paste it directly into your HTTP Request file for it to be converted into its format, and then feel free to modify request params, headers, or body</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
	</releases>
	<project_license>LicenseRef-proprietary</project_license>
	<developer_name>JetBrains s.r.o.</developer_name>
	<screenshots>
		<screenshot type="default">
			<image type="source">https://resources.jetbrains.com/help/img/idea/2024.1/py_new_ui_overview.png</image>
			<caption>New tool window layout</caption>
		</screenshot>
		<screenshot>
			<image type="source">https://resources.jetbrains.com/help/img/idea/2024.1/py_new_ui_dark_theme.png</image>
			<caption>Themes, icons, fonts</caption>
		</screenshot>
	</screenshots>
	<content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
</component>
